Ruishi Zou Curriculum Vitæ

Google Scholar: Ruishi Zou Department of Computer Science and Technology Website: motion115.github.io College of Electronic and Information Engineering Email: ruishi.ray.zou@gmail.com

Tongji University

Linkedin: motion115 No.4800 Cao'an Highway, Jiading District, Shanghai, China. 201804

# Research Statement

My research interest is designing mix-initiative systems to enhance human (lay users and domain experts) capabilities through interacting with AI technologies (NLP, CV, etc.). I approach human-AI interaction by exploring the design of information-based interfaces powered by AI's knowledge representation capabilities. I hope to contribute to research fields in HCI such as visualization and user interface software and technology through technical and empirical methods.

### Education

2020-2024 B.E. in Computer Science and Technology, Tongji University, Shanghai, China.

GPA: 4.69/5 (Equivalent to 91.86/100)

### **Publications**

[P.3] More Samples or More Prompt Inputs? Exploring Effective In-Context Sampling for LLM Few-Shot Prompt Engineering.

Bingsheng Yao; Guiming Chen; Ruishi Zou; Yuxuan Lu; Jiachen Li; Shao Zhang; Sijia Liu; James Hendler; Dakuo Wang **NAACL 2024 Findings** DOI: 10.48550/arXiv.2311.09782.

[P.2] iTutor: A Generative Tutorial System for Teaching the Elders to Use Smartphone Applications.

Ruishi Zou; Zi Ye; Chen Ye.

ACM UIST 2023 Adjunct (Poster Extended Abstract)

GitHub: Motion115/iTutor. Project: motion115.github.io/iTutor. DOI: 10.1145/3586182.3616663.

[P.1] Chart2Vec: A Universal Embedding of Context-Aware Visualizations.

Qing Chen; Ying Chen; Ruishi Zou; Wei Shuai; Yi Guo; Jiazhe Wang; Nan Cao.

Under review at IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (2024)

GitHub: idvxlab/chart2vec. Project: chart2vec.idvxlab.com. DOI: 10.48550/arXiv.2306.08304 (Before revision).

# **Professional Experience**

2023.10-Present Research Assistant, Human-Centered AI Lab, Northeastern University, Remote

Advisor: Prof. Dakuo Wang • In-Context Sampling [P.3]: Conducted experiments to benchmark the In-Context Sampling (ICS) strategy on

- various large language models and tasks; Implemented sampling strategy used with ICS.
- Research Assistant, Student Innovation Center of CEIE, Tongji University, Shanghai, China 2023.4 -Present Advisor: Prof. Chen Ye
  - iTutor: A Generative Tutorial System for Teaching the Elders to Use Smartphone Applications [P.2]: Proposed a method leveraging large language models that support UI image-to-instruction generation to facilitate elders in using smartphone applications; Coordinated a team of four to participate in the China Collegiate Computing Contest - HCI Innovation Competition 2023 and was awarded third prize.
- 2023.4 -2023.10 Research Intern, Computer Music Group, Carnegie Mellon University, Remote Advisor: Prof. Roger B. Dannenberg
  - Music Patterns and Music Models: Explored using neural networks to perform order selection across various orders of Markov models; Slightly outperformed the best single model benchmark.
- Research Intern, Intelligent Big Data Visualization Lab, Tongji University, Shanghai, China Advisor: Prof. Qing Chen and Prof. Nan Cao
  - Chart2Vec: A Universal Embedding of Context-Aware Visualizations [P.1]: Assisted in the training and evaluation (quantitative and qualitative) of the Chart2Vec model, a context-aware representation learning model for chart specifications that could support various applications such as visualization recommendation.
  - Chart2Vec Production Deployment (2023.7 2023.9, AntV Team, Ant Group, Shanghai, China)

# **Selected Projects**

[SP.3]	UI2Vec: A Multimodal Embedding Method for Robust UI Classification
2023.3 - 2023.6	Venue: Multimedia Course Project
	Advisor: Prof. Hanli Wang, Tongji University
	GitHub: Motion115/UI2Vec. Report: Technical Report (Chinese)
[SP.2]	Forest Orchestra – Interactive Conducting Game for Music Education
2022.9 - 2022.12	Venue: China Collegiate Computing Contest - HCI Innovation Competition 2022
	Advisor: Prof. Yinan Zhang, Tongji University
[SP.1] 2022.5 - 2023.3	Data-driven Approach on Identifying Systemic Financial Risk
	Venue: Student Innovation Training Program (2022 - 2023 Academic Year)
	Advisor: Prof. Dawei Cheng, Tongji University

## Awards and Honors

- 2023 Undergraduate Academic Star of College of Electronic and Information Engineering, Tongji University, 2023
- 2023 **Third Price**, China Collegiate Computing Contest HCI Innovation Competition 2023 **(top 3%, 16 38 out of 1,388 entries) [P.2]**
- 2022 Third-Class Scholarship, Tongji University Outstanding Student Scholarship, 2021 2022 Academic Year
- 2022 "Award in Creativity", China Collegiate Computing Contest HCI Innovation Competition 2022 (top 4%, 39 41 out of 1,170 entries) [SP.2]
- 2021 First-Class Scholarship, Tongji University Outstanding Student Scholarship, 2020 2021 Academic Year

### Skills

### **English Skills**

TOEFL 108/120 (Reading 30, Listening 29, Speaking 24, Writing 25)

GRE 327/340 (Verbal Reasoning 159/170, Quantitative Reasoning 168/170, Analytical Writing 4/6)

### **Practical Skills**

 $Programming\ Languages:\ Python,\ JavaScript/TypeScript,\ HTML,\ C/C++,\ LaTeX$ 

Libraries/Platforms (progressively learning): React, d3.js, PyTorch

Ruishi Zou | Curriculum Vitæ Last updated: March, 2024 | 2 of 2